SAIFUL ISLAM

B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering +8801736175704 em_saiful.islam@yahoo.com Dhaka, Barishal, Bangladesh, 8250



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly capable, versatile and accomplished IT Engineer with more than 4 years extensive management experience, planning and implementing computer systems and networks. I have indepth knowledge of IT Implementation and customer service, and troubleshooting skills for networking & Computers, and end-user problems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Executive Mar 2022 - Present

Interstoff Group (South East Textiles (Pvt.) Ltd.) • Tangail, Bangladesh

- Managing the development of new products or services to meet user needs.
- Managing operations such as computer networks, hardware, software, and other IT infrastructure to ensure it is functioning properly.
- Developing and implementing policy related to information security and privacy concerns.
- Identifying potential problems with existing systems and recommending improvements to existing processes.
- Researching new technologies and products that could help the company achieve its goals.
- · Reviewing current systems and recommending changes to management.
- Establishing policies and procedures for an organization's computing needs.
- Implementing new technologies to improve efficiency and productivity.

IT Officer Sep 2018 - Feb 2022

Onetex Limited • Gazipur, Bangladesh

- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers, CCTV
 Cameras and scanners.
- Monitoring and maintaining computer systems, server computer and networks.
- Responding in a timely manner to service issues and requests.
- Providing technical support across the company (this may be in person or over the phone.
- Repairing and replacing equipment as necessary & testing new technology.
- · Possibly training more junior staff members.
- To Perform Any Other Jobs As and When Advised By the Higher Authority.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

Daffodil International University • Dhaka, Bangladesh

Jan 2015 - Apr 2019

SKILLS

Technical Support · Problem Solving · Windows Server · IT Service Management · Networking · IT Integration · IT Hardware Support & Troubleshooting.

PROFESSIONAL CREDENTIALS

· IT Support Service

VOLUNTEER WORK

Sense of Social Responsibility

Jan 2012 - Apr 2012

Youth Ending Hunger Project • Dhaka, Bangladesh

Donating blood, Recycling, planting trees, picking up trash, Helping out the poor, international development, Volunteer firefighting.

AWARDS AND HONOURS

Best Employee of the year

2020

Onetex Limited. Gazipur, Dhaka